<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text"></title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<<<<<<< HEAD
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000" />
<updated>2018-08-08T23:48:15+05:30</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
=======
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://blog.wncc-iitb.org/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.wncc-iitb.org" />
<updated>2018-08-09T14:09:04+05:30</updated>
<id>https://blog.wncc-iitb.org/</id>
>>>>>>> pr/3
<author>
  <name>Web and Coding Club</name>
  <uri>https://blog.wncc-iitb.org/</uri>
  <email>locacocinero@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kumar Ayush's Internship]]></title>
  <link>http://localhost:4000/internship/luxembourg-cheeku</link>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/internship/luxembourg-cheeku</id>
  <published>2017-07-13T00:00:00+05:30</published>
  <updated>2017-07-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Web and Coding Club</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>locacocinero@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I worked as a Summer Research Intern à la Université du Luxembourg. My primary area of research was Non-Equilibrium Transport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before applying for this position, I worked as a freelance developer and worked on computational astrophysics projects. In my fifth semester, I was applying for internship positions in two different areas. The first were game development companies in Mumbai and the US. Second, astronomy and astrophysics departments all around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of places in India might have provided me a better professional work exposure in some specific research areas. But going abroad for an internship is also a cultural experience, and deserves advantage of choice. 
I did not have luck with my applications before I got the offer for Luxembourg. This was an application I filled through the PT cell. The group works in the area of mesoscopic physics. They are aligned towards theory and far from my primary interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started to believe that sticking to my interests is arrogant. It would be a good idea to try new things when I am young. In retrospect, it was a good idea to keep my personal preferences aside.
About the Group
The group is led by Prof. Thomas Schmidt, and I would quote his homepage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Within this project about modern mesoscopic systems, my group investigates topological insulators, one-dimensional quantum systems, as well as nanomechanical systems in the quantum regime.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;about-the-work&quot;&gt;About the Work&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;my-work-space&quot;&gt;My Work Space&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;.././images/cheeku_intern_pic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My Work Space&quot; title=&quot;My Work Space&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My broad area of specialization was Non-Equilibrium Transport. I studied the transport of non-interacting fermions through a quantum dot in tunneling contact with two (or more) reservoirs at varying chemical potentials. More specificially, I attempted to calculate time-dependent current-current correlation or “noise” for the current flowing through the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a course on Theoretical Condensed Matter Physics in my sixth semester, and did a course project on Green’s Functions in CMP. These greatly aided my intern work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;daily-life&quot;&gt;Daily Life&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a residence provided by the university and is located 300 m away from my work desk. Me, Anuj and Amal lived together in the same residence. It is convenient. All stores close around 7 PM. It is harder to get used to this than I imagined. The sun sets around 10:30 PM. This has a good advantage. More hours of daylight do equate to more work getting done. As human beings, affinity to sunlight is real. It was amazing to see my body taking over my mind which is tuned to living like a caveman. I enjoyed the sun. We had breakfast around 8 AM, reached our desks around 9 AM, lunch at noon, work till about 6 PM, then cook dinner together, and then sleep. Cooking saves money, requires a  lot of time. Hence, we used to have lunch in the university canteen which was an array of European cuisine, while cooking Indian food for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;travel&quot;&gt;Travel&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schengen is a small village and commune in South-Eastern Luxembourg. Their wine and VISA are very good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our major travels can be described as Paris, Amsterdam, Cologne and small towns in the Moselle Valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;social&quot;&gt;Social&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have made good relations with a lot of people in the University. Enough of them will likely last an eternity, at least in our memories. The most mature friendship I had was with Anuj’s professor and the HoD here, Prof. Ludger Wirtz. We had no professional things to discuss. We work on different things. All our discussions used to be about light topics or heavy philosophies.
Every Tuesday, me and Anuj went to a local Board Games meetup. We went to some other local events and parties as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;thank-you-for-reading&quot;&gt;Thank you for reading!&lt;/h1&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/internship/luxembourg-cheeku&quot;&gt;Kumar Ayush's Internship&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Web and Coding Club at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on July 13, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nihal's internship at Mercari '18]]></title>
  <link>https://blog.wncc-iitb.org/internship/nihal-mercari.html</link>
  <id>https://blog.wncc-iitb.org/internship/nihal-mercari</id>
  <published>2018-07-16T00:00:00+05:30</published>
  <updated>2018-07-16T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Web and Coding Club</name>
    <uri>https://blog.wncc-iitb.org</uri>
    <email>locacocinero@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following has been adapted from the author’s blog. Access the original version &lt;a href=&quot;https://nihal111.github.io/2018/07/09/mercari-internship.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m back in Mumbai as I write this recap blog post describing my summer spent in the heart of Tokyo, during my internship at Mercari. This blog post is going to be specific to my internship. I’ve written about my travelling experiences in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://nihal111.github.io/2018/07/09/japan-lookback.html&quot;&gt;different post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-mercari&quot;&gt;About Mercari&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mercari is a CtoC marketplace startup that was founded in 2013. Their main product is the Mercari CtoC marketplace app. In just 5 years, the company has skyrocketed to become Japan’s largest community-driven marketplace. The company also gained the pre-IPO unicorn status, being a privately held company valued over $1 billion. This was before the company went public this June on the Toyko Stock Exchange’s Mothers Market, during my stay there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-office&quot;&gt;The Office&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nihal111.github.io/img/mercari/officeview.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Office View&quot; title=&quot;Office View&quot; style=&quot;max-height: 500px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mercari office is located on the 18th floor of Mori Tower, the 6th tallest building in Tokyo. The view from the office is fantastic and the breeze on the top, at the observation deck is better. There is a giant spider outside the office, that should remind you of &lt;a href=&quot;http://silverscreensnobs.com/spiders-doppelgangers-secrets-enemy-expained/&quot;&gt;Enemy&lt;/a&gt; if you’re into sci-fi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nihal111.github.io/img/mercari/moritower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mori Tower&quot; title=&quot;Mori Tower&quot; style=&quot;max-height: 500px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://nihal111.github.io/img/mercari/spider.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;spider&quot; title=&quot;Spider&quot; style=&quot;max-height: 500px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-honeymoon-phase&quot;&gt;The Honeymoon Phase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first week was nothing short of overwhelming. Even for the honeymoon phase, things seemed too good to be true. The onboarding and orientation were smooth, and we were given our gear. We got company phones, portable wifi and the $2000 MacBook Pro amongst other goodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nihal111.github.io/img/mercari/gear.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gear&quot; title=&quot;Gear&quot; style=&quot;max-height: 500px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were assigned to our teams but were supposed to go through a week of orientation before beginning any work. The Global Operations Team took special effort to make us feel at home. They organised the multiple onboarding sessions and even took us out for a complete Tokyo tour on a weekday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nihal111.github.io/img/mercari/tokyotour.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tokyo Tour&quot; title=&quot;Tokyo Tour&quot; style=&quot;max-height: 500px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By week two, we were on our desks at our respective teams with the welcome balloons we received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nihal111.github.io/img/mercari/balloons.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Balloons&quot; title=&quot;Balloons&quot; style=&quot;max-height: 500px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-android-team&quot;&gt;The Android Team&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the pleasure to work with the JP Android Team, the team working on the main marketplace app- &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.kouzoh.mercari&quot;&gt;Mercari&lt;/a&gt; for Japan. It was a medium sized team with just over 10 people. The bulk of my task for the summer was to implement client facing feature on the Android app. I also worked on a few isolated issues all over the codebase and took the initiative to improve the code quality in the codebase which was very well received by the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nihal111.github.io/img/mercari/androidteam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Android Team&quot; title=&quot;Android Team&quot; style=&quot;max-height: 500px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My team was largely global, consisting of a large number of Gaijins (Japanese for foreigners). I benefited hugely from this and learned how to work in a multi-cultural team. I learned the flow for how a spec moves to feature that gets shipped and how each detail in the middle matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the technical side, for the first time I &lt;strong&gt;implemented a software architecture&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;wrote Kotlin code&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;wrote Unit tests using Mockito and Robolectric&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;created an automation task using CI&lt;/strong&gt;. I’m glad to have been able to achieve this in a small period of just over a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nihal111.github.io/img/mercari/desk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Desk&quot; title=&quot;Desk&quot; style=&quot;max-height: 500px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My team was great in many ways, apart from the mentor lunches that all of us interns were entitled to, the Android team had a weekly team lunch. My team even put together a special farewell dinner for me, after which we ended up going to Karaoke. There was also this beautiful parting gift I received from my team-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://nihal111.github.io/img/mercari/rum.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rum&quot; title=&quot;rum&quot; style=&quot;max-height: 500px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;experience&quot;&gt;Experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, the whole experience over the course of my internship was more than I could have asked for. Mercari was great to me, and it was a crazy time to be there. Amidst the whole IPO frenzy and the company celebrating its 5th anniversary, I was lucky to go to all the parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned how to work efficiently in a team, picked up on a few technical things, got to meet a whole bunch of great people, got exposed to a whole new culture and travelled as much as I could (more about that &lt;a href=&quot;https://nihal111.github.io/2018/07/09/japan-lookback.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summer of ‘18 was one of the best summers I’ve had so far. Being home feels warm but itchy.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.wncc-iitb.org/internship/nihal-mercari.html&quot;&gt;Nihal's internship at Mercari '18&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Web and Coding Club at &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.wncc-iitb.org&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on July 16, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>
